A face... a fleet... a wall... a
man...
A trick... a trick to break the walls of
Troy.
And burn it.
Scream into the ground.
What does
it mean?
A gift... for Athena.
Common gods.
Respect their offering.
Save it from the waves.
Take it to Athena's temple.
The war is over.
Not this song.
Remind them of who's wine they're
drinking.
I don't want to deceive this song.
I want to deceive us.
Why do you entertain shooters in his house
night after night?
In this world, a man does what he chooses.
I do what I can.
I am a man.
Now I'm all.
So throw them out.
Break Zeus' law and see what they do to
you if you give them that excuse.
I've already lost a husband.
I don't want to lose a son.
My dad's coming back.
And where is he?
Eight years since Troy fell.
Almost twenty since he left us.
Where is he?
We
welcomed all of you.
Are you calling us beggars?
I'm saying you've been welcome here for
three years.
We've only enjoyed your hospitality for so
long.
Because your mother won't choose.
She's already married.
Odysseus is dead.
What do you know about my dad?
I know he kept stringing cattle in the bad
wine.
You had the best of it the first two
seasons.
I know he never came home.
Not yet.
You're pining for a daddy you didn't even
know.
Like some sniffling bastard.
Well, since none of us can really know who
our fathers are.
Don't cling to no one.
But I did know him.
As boys.
We watched him hunt.
I tried to volunteer for his expedition to
Troy.
He told me to stay here and keep an eye on
you.
Oh, me or my mother?
You can't blame me for looking.
My dad is coming home.
And his hospitality won't be as generous
as hers.
So he doesn't follow Zeus' law then?
Zeus' law tells us to treat strangers as
we be treated because they might be gods
in disguise.
I think we've established to antennae us
that you were not a god.
This one certainly doesn't smell like a
god.
Wouldn't be much of a disguise if he did.
Careful.
He might strike you down right now.
Connor.
That thunder was luck.
I don't know.
You have wise eyes.
Themis eyes.
Here, you see all the traitors?
From Sparta.
Has Menelaus come home from the war?
Years ago.
Oh, did Zeus never came back?
We don't even know if he's alive.
Have you heard anything?
The song of how he won the war.
We've all heard that.
Anything else?
No.
But...
Sparta is full of Trojan War veterans.
Someone will know something.
You will this is his son?
Go to Sparta.
Go.
See Menelaus.
He'd welcome you.
The queen wants to speak to the stranger.
She lifts her nose.
Just don't try to give her any false hope.
She has some way of knowing whether a
person has actually seen Odysseus.
You see that, man?
He can't see much anymore, but that
doesn't stop him beating travelers to
death in exchange for lies about my
father.
No, no, too fast.
How can you know?
You don't need eyes to hear a hasty
combination.
Mentor push him.
No.
No, too fast.
He's as friendly as you.
He only answered to your father.
Where'd he get him from?
He met right here.
Come on.
Ah.
I'll take him.
For your boy?
We're a hunting dog.
Damned if he wasn't right.
Hold him still.
How bad a scar do you want?
Why do you always pluck your bow?
It's only fair.
To warn your prey?
To fight with honor.
You weren't fighting, you were hunting.
Hunting's nothing.
Fighting with stealth.
Clever.
Clever, but your cleverness is going to
get you in trouble.
Try again.
This time, not as fast or precise.
You can't win with a perfect defense.
Draw the attack.
How?
Hesitate.
Open your belly to your opponent's blade.
Their attack becomes your chance.
You teach my father that?
No, no, he taught me.
He said, you're not always going to be the
strongest or the fastest, so be the
smartest.
What would he do, huh?
If he came back here to find all these
suitors in his house?
Don't.
I can't even let myself imagine what he'd
do to them.
There are so many.
Cut a couple down, the others cave.
Bullies and bullies.
Cowards.
Most of them are old enough to go to Troy,
but when they saw Agamemnon's sail,
their fathers hit them.
And you knew Agamemnon's war would take
many years and many lives.
So he raised his army by lottery.
Name?
Draw.
No.
Name?
Antinous.
Draw.
Yes.
By lots?
Antinous told me he volunteered.
Your boy's trying to take Sinon's place.
I'm not going to let him.
He needs to stay here, take care of his
family.
You can watch over your boy, too,
of course.
He's with me.
He wanted Antinous to look after me.
No, no, no.
But Odysseus was sensitive to a father's
shame.
He felt for these fathers.
You and your mother meant more to him than
promises of glory.
So he knew it would be years.
Did he tell my mother?
That's a question for her.
You miss.
Is he ever coming back?
Hargis thinks so.
Never known a dog reach 20.
But he's long not lived his master.
I didn't mean to stop you.
I'm in no hurry.
The elder's decreed when I finish your
grandfather's burial shroud, it'll be time
to remarry.
Why?
If it has been without a king too long,
they want security.
From what?
The people from the sea.
That's just travelers' tales.
All we know of the world is travelers'
tales.
That's how we found Dr. I.
and Paulin.
Now they all tell stories of attacks by
people from the sea.
And who are the people from the sea?
No one knows, but the elders wanted they
could be prepared.
Prepared?
Part of the greatest civilization ever
known.
Look at this great house.
Stone's as old as knowledge.
At the mercy of some greedy, unwanted
guests.
The structure's nothing.
Without people's respect for its meaning.
It was Zeus's law.
To treat others as he would be treated.
And they abuse that, they destroy
everything.
So how could you think of marrying one of
them?
Because a long time ago, your father asked
me to.
Agamemnon is our king.
And the Trojans took his brother's wife.
Well, she ran away with them.
Either way, the walls of Troy are said to
be impregnable.
We'll sit outside that great city trying
to draw them into battle.
As the years go by, and Telemachus grows,
and you learn life without me.
Menelaus will give up on Helen.
This is Agamemnon's excuse to break Troy's
control of the trading routes.
He won't let it pass.
Ever.
Who have you refused?
He'll take our son.
He would never.
He sacrificed his own daughter for
favorable winds.
Well, the gods want his daughter's life.
The power of a sacrifice is in the cost to
the person making it.
It's monstrous.
And committed.
I won't return soon.
If at all.
What have we ran?
Took you past the ship, the brightest
crew, and ahead for the horizon.
Held hands on deck as we rode west at
dusk, chasing the escaping sun.
There's a world beyond these walls.
Agamemnon's vengeance would fall on all of
it, the god.
And I promise me, if I don't return,
by the time Telemachus comes of age,
promise me, you'll take another husband.
Enough sacrifice.
Love's not a sacrifice.
Of course it is.
I don't want you to make it.
It's not up to you.
Promise me.
No.
Promise me you'll come back.
What if I can't?
Then your memory won't be making my
decisions.
Take my pen.
Wear it.
Always.
Athena will bring you home.
I'm not sure it suits me.
My drablers claim to have seen you.
I'll ask where you were wearing,
but I'll know if they're lying.
If the people from the sea are real,
right now, Ithaca has no king or as an
army.
I could take this room.
Come.
String it.
That's not fair.
You said only he could string this bow.
He was happy to let others try.
Really?
He'd line up all the axes.
No one else ever did it.
Mom, they're bleeding us dry, so you'll be
forced to choose one of them before I can
claim the throne myself.
The traveler told me Menelaus returned
years ago.
They've all returned.
All who survived.
Maybe he is dead.
And if he is, then this is my palace.
We need to know.
I have to go to Menelaus to find out the
truth.
Do that because these suitors mean you
harm.
Oh, you think I don't know that?
Every night they push me to give them the
excuse they need.
And out there on the sea, on the road,
they won't need an excuse.
You just won't come back.
You don't want me to claim the throne
myself.
You just want to keep me in my place so
that you can stay Queen of Ithaca.
I've had enough of being Queen of Ithaca
without my king!
Without your king?
Or a king?
And you think you're ready to take your
father's place?
Your child.
Out in the land he is.
Don't wear your spurs in the palace.
You're a cowherd, not a horseman.
And you're a pig farmer, and who are you
to talk to me like that?
A servant our master left in charge of his
herdsmen.
The master is long gone.
You're blind or full.
And you're about as welcome here as that
doggess.
Argus!
Sorry.
He didn't do anything.
So that stink is you?
He be old dog alone.
Which one?
Both of us.
What did you say to him, slave?
He just got carried away.
Argus is my father's hunting dog.
It's hunting dog.
Look at that thing.
Get it out of here.
Don't catch his ears in pain.
Okay.
You're not put it out of his misery.
Leave him alone!
You all see?
Please don't hurt my son.
Easy, easy.
All of us.
Young pup lost his head.
Show us some mercy.
Drink some more of his wine.
I'll take care of this.
It's my father's hunting dog.
He's only living to see Odysseus return.
It's fine.
I'll put him on the dung heap out front so
he can greet his master a little sooner.
That dog stays out there!
Next time think twice before we rough up
your life for an animal.
I'll
take them down to the ship, still no one.
You're the only people you trust.
You break your mother's heart.
If I stay, they'll force me to fight.
No one will back me.
I have to find out what happened to my
father.
Ithica will be behind me if they know
Odysseus is dead.
The suitors will never allow that.
You will never make it back.
Tell them, T'or.
Tell them to meet the ships just before
dawn.
What do you want me to tell your mother?
Hold out for as long as you can.
Ship's ready.
Tide's right.
Have I ever told you that you have wise
eyes, Athena's eyes?
Once or twice.
You haven't even asked me where we're
going yet.
Where are we going?
We'll find my dad.
He's alive.
I can feel it in the wind and the waves.
He's out there somewhere, wandering,
injured, lost.
I don't know.
But he's alive.
More dreams?
Men drowning.
Inside.
Some...
dark space.
Firelight on stone.
I don't know.
Don't you want to remember?
Why can't God speak in ways we understand?
Who doesn't understand, Bender?
The fire.
A child's smile.
A good harvest.
You hide yourselves from us.
Look.
We're smoothing that cloud.
Massing those birds.
We're smoothing the water.
What were you talking to?
Athena came to me again.
She's telling me to remember.
To leave.
Why would you leave?
We have everything we need.
How long have I been here?
Collapsed.
I have a home somewhere.
There's someone...
out there.
How do you know?
I don't know.
I feel.
What we have here could last forever.
Forever is for God.
For your God.
You want to remember, but what if
remembering destroys your happiness?
Then it wasn't real.
No.
No more.
But I love it.
Stop eating the lotus.
Tell me what you remember.
After Troy.
Troy.
We won the war.
And then what?
Ten years on this fucking beach.
Let's go home.
Remember who we leave here.
Do we have enough provisions?
We've taken enough from Troy.
Another stop or two won't kill us.
It's still the oars.
We'll raise the sail.
Follow the southerly winds.
Yes, sir.
Agamemnon's rowing west on the known
provisions route.
He's got more mouths to feed.
We'll find places to limp.
Are you sure it's a risk?
That's all that Agamemnon long enough.
With little luck and the right winds,
we'll see some of the world still be home
before Agamemnon.
Come on.
Just keep the bear on the right.
Oh, this is land!
See?
Lucky bastard.
We're down to our last supplies.
Assemble a landing party, food and water,
and up for three weeks.
What if it won't give it?
How badly do you want to get home?
Get your weapons ready!
Agamemnon, move in!
Borrowing.
Ask him why they abandoned their village
instead of welcoming us.
No.
We're Greeks.
From Ithaca.
Maybe you heard our victory at Troy.
We're headed west on the southerly winds.
If you get caught, you won't be able to
escape.
You won't like what you'll find there.
He says if we go that way, we won't like
the things we'll find.
After years of war, no one could stand
between my men and home.
Not even me.
Then something happened.
Chasing the escaping sun.
Where?
There you go.
Lucky bastard.
Sheep coming flocks.
Let's follow.
Someone lives here.
Yeah, they make cheese.
Pretty good.
There's a lot of it.
We should leave.
We brought nothing to trade with.
Zeus' law.
I don't know if whoever lives here has
heard of Zeus' law or Zeus, for that
matter.
Everyone's heard of Zeus' law.
Get the fire going.
We'll welcome the owner back.
Get away from the fire.
No!
I think it's asleep.
Wait!
The rock.
We can't move the rock.
We'll be trapped.
Spread the word in the morning.
When it lets out its flock, we'll rush the
entrance.
Pressed up.
Can we jam something in the cave mouth?
Leave a gap.
Maybe.
But what?
There's law.
It'll notice.
But grab the thin end.
Put it in the fire.
How much rope do we have?
How big is the flock?
A couple dozen, maybe.
Not too many of us.
When it comes back, two of us have to get
out.
Or at least get killed.
Run low through the flock towards the
entrance and then split wide.
So we can only grab one of them.
Right.
Four of us should make the run.
Two and two.
We're warming up the two before he sleeps.
What about his body?
What about it?
We just leave him here to run.
That's food for that thing?
We honor our dead Odysseus.
He died helping us escape.
We'll honor him by escaping.
He can talk.
Why didn't he talk before?
Do you talk to Hans?
Should we reason with it?
I think we're past that.
What are you doing?
No!
Why
do you have to fire that arrow?
You lost good soldiers to that beast.
Yeah, and that beast was a son up beside
him.
What?
When we put its eye out, we heard it
crying his name.
That thing was a monster.
I heard it, too.
So now the sea is against us?
And the wind.
Are we supposed to get home with Poseidon
against us?
We can't live by omens and sacrifices.
Do you know how many times I've heard you
weeping, praying to Athena since we left
Troy?
Couldn't you have shown some mercy?
Take this.
Wear it.
To remember those we couldn't bury.
The gods help those who help themselves.
From that moment, every rough sea or
headwind told the crew we were cursed.
But where is my crew?
When will you let me see my men?
If I could just talk to them, they'd help
me remember.
Did I have a wife, children, maybe a son?
How long have I been here?
A long time.
If I had a son, how old would he be now?
I don't know how to speak to a king.
You'll be fine.
Keep your mouth shut.
But if anyone asks, we're traitors from
Crete, then we'll figure out how to
approach the king.
Thank you.
You seem to be having quite...
This way.
Where are you taking us?
The king insists on meeting strangers
himself.
You sit.
Not you.
You.
Enjoy our hospitality.
As soon as it demands.
But perhaps you'll tell us who you are.
You picked the right day to arrive.
Feast at my daughter's wedding.
Tomorrow she leaves to start a new life.
You don't look like a beggar.
Imagine you know who I am.
And now I asked the son of Atreus,
brother of Vagamemnon, a husband of Helen.
Perhaps you've heard of Helen.
Feast.
I launched a thousand ships.
That may be now just 500.
Somebody left on the battlefields of Troy
for that face.
For your brother's ambition.
This one looks familiar.
Hey, Jacks.
Trocolus.
Achilles.
I don't miss him as much as one particular
warrior.
He's the smartest of us all.
Ten years we've rotted on that beach.
Fighting amongst ourselves until one day.
He found a way.
Odysseus.
Did you hear the story of the horse?
I did hear it from the inside.
We were in there for days.
We squeezed inside before the ship set
sail.
Odysseus, he knew that no one could know
that we were inside, not even sinning the
soldier we left behind.
The first two tides are men drowned right
in front of us.
They're silent.
They're pissed at shit.
A gift.
Common gods.
Respect their offering.
He knew the wait for a moonless night
around the plains of Troy.
Filling
it.
You sure you're the bard singing?
I have.
But they weren't there, it was all of you.
It was your father, Odysseus.
You're so like him.
When did you last see him?
Troy.
God's will.
God's granted us a righteous victory.
Righteous.
The gods granted our righteous victory,
but did not bless our voyages.
Took me years to get home.
And he didn't.
Some did, in which they hadn't.
Tell him.
Tell him about your brother.
About the fate that the gods bestowed on
him after your righteous struggle.
About his heroes welcome.
About how Agamemnon made it home years
before us.
Tell him how he was welcomed by his queen,
my twin sister, Clytemnestra.
No, no.
Tell him how she...
No!
He does not want to hear about my brother!
What's the news of his father?
I know nothing of Odysseus, since Troy.
Nothing?
Not from any of your men.
Our Agamemmons were traitors and
travelers.
Did you come here for summers?
Is that what you're interested in,
gossip?
You're in the right place.
Anyone want to spin a story about
Odysseus?
Some say he's rich or some say poor.
Some say he perished, some say he's
imprisoned.
What say you?
Imprisoned.
What kind of prison?
An old man like that.
Tell me what you do remember.
The rest will come.
And the man became more and more convinced
that I defended Poseidon.
We were hit by storm after storm,
all pushing us off course, until we were
truly lost.
Hello.
We're here in peace.
We just need some food.
We need food!
Can you understand that?
It's just a child.
Is that a child?
What about its parents?
Hey, shh, it's okay.
No, no, no, no.
Shhh!
Back to the ship!
Turn to port, follow the coast.
What if they have ships?
We need to get as far away as possible.
We don't have supplies for a block.
We need to find crossing.
We've lost our way.
We need to find food and get our bearings.
Turn to port.
There!
Come on, there!
Go past, we'll find anchorage at the
beach.
We're done!
Form a landing party.
Tomorrow.
Leave someone with the tenders.
We think you should stay.
We?
All of us.
Still alive.
Is this a mutiny?
That's up to you.
Give me your boat.
I'll make sure we eat tonight.
No matter what you find.
No, no, no, it's okay!
It's okay!
You're okay!
It's all right!
No one's gonna hurt you!
If I do what you want.
No one is going to hurt you.
My name's your Ilocus.
What's your name?
Cersei.
Cersei?
We need food.
Badly.
We have food.
Lucky.
It's food.
You let me.
Your weapons.
We're armor.
Put it out the back.
Do you like my meat?
Why?
Do you have so much?
You never know when strangers will come.
What's their appetite?
Too much is never enough.
Ilocus!
Don't
move!
No!
Give me your dagger.
Stay with the boat!
Why don't you just come here?
Did you come from the sea?
Are you alone?
My pigs have taken a liking to you.
Are you hungry?
Leave your weapons at the door.
Enjoy the hospitality of Zeus.
Grab a hog.
You can slaughter it for your dinner.
Whoever you are, you're clearly not a
farmer.
Here.
That stew smells good.
That's enough for just us.
Who says it's just us?
Who else is here?
Who indeed.
You say you're all alone.
But no one comes here alone.
No?
You can only reach this spot by sea.
So how do you get there?
So where are your shipmates?
I'm looking for them.
Anyone happy to come this way?
But you've prepared all this food.
You're questioning me?
You?
A traveler who's clearly starving.
It hasn't touched the food in front of
him.
Claims to be a sailor.
Yet we're as a great warrior's armor.
And who breaks Zeus' law.
By bringing a dagger into his hostess's
house.
You have sharp eyes.
Sharpened by the gods.
Do they grant you insights?
Truths.
Sometimes.
Would they tell you where I could find my
men?
Your men.
That's right.
They would.
Then would you tell me?
Perhaps.
If you give me your dagger.
Fire refuses my hospitality.
Leaving their rings.
Don't!
I don't know who this crow is to you.
You don't put that knife down.
I will throttle it to find out.
Don't hurt him.
Family.
Mother.
Your sister.
You did this to her like you turned my men
into piths.
I didn't turn your men into anything.
Look at them.
This is who they are.
Base.
Disgusting.
Primal urges that you value in battle.
They've raped and pillaged across the
world for you.
And you think that's against their nature?
You think they only did that because you
ordered them to?
A true commander thinks his men's savagery
is actually discipline.
If you don't seem that deluded.
But you sent them to me here.
On my own.
A gang of filthy soldiers with empty
bellies and hot blood.
You thought they'd respect me and my home?
Look at them.
Know your own men.
Did they hurt you?
They would have.
They just want to go home.
Let them.
Come back.
Back into your disguise.
Odysseus.
Back to the ship.
Take all the food you can carry.
Leave the meat.
You're not going to let her live.
She's a witch.
Who gave her powers?
Your gods.
Fill the jugs and skins of the stream.
Be ready to sail at dawn.
Well, I leave her like this.
We get on better this way.
I'm sorry if we offended you.
We can't get back without your help.
We need to know the way to the trade
routes.
You're too lost.
What do you mean?
Only blind Thereseus can tell you how to
go home.
Thereseus?
In Hades.
Nobody sails into hell.
Then comes back.
You will.
Head north into the twilight.
And head inland until the river of fire
meets the river of ice.
There you must dig a trench.
And fill it with the blood of sacrifice.
Gather the dead.
And learn how you go home.
You.
Not your men.
You curse them?
Not a curse.
A truth.
Your men don't want you to defy the gods.
The gods say only you make it home.
Then I defy the gods.
Sinai.
It's Odysseus.
Odysseus.
Sinai.
It's Odysseus.
Let him drink Odysseus.
Then you will hear his testimony.
Odysseus.
Yes.
He lied to everyone.
Did you have to lie to me?
I needed you to believe.
Why did you have to volunteer?
Don't you remember how I came here?
I begged to take Intinuous's place.
He'd been called.
He offered money for your family if you
take his place.
If the Trojans don't let me live.
If I never make it home.
Take this back to my father.
Tell him everything I did.
Odysseus.
Feel free to add some stuff.
You didn't trust me with the truth?
You knew I'd die for you.
Dying meant the truth I needed you to
believe.
I died for your lie on that beach.
I know.
I was there with you.
I heard you repeat the lie with your dying
breath.
Winning us the war.
I was right there, inches from you,
smelling your blood.
What comfort could that give me?
Not knowing you were inside that horse
until the dead told me.
Which dead?
A lot of veterans of your campaigns walk
these shores.
The dead meet to lament the living and
greet the newly dead.
My father was the first shade to find me.
To comfort you?
Shades don't comfort.
They want word of the living who wronged
them.
My father had died in poverty.
Alone, begging for scraps from people like
Antinous.
Antinous cheated you?
As he's no doubt cheating you.
How?
Who's inethica looking after your wife and
son?
My wife is of no concern.
Talk to Agamonon about homecomings.
Agamonon's here?
You buried me at Troy with respect.
Thank you.
But spare a thought for those you didn't.
It's not always possible.
When you get home, take a ship,
head into the unknown west till you find
land.
And there, give sacrifice and honor your
men.
Do you still have the lot?
Of course.
If you make it home, give Antinous back
his shame.
I will.
My lord.
Odysseus.
How are you here?
We won the war, you headed for home.
Odysseus.
The most brilliant of all my generals.
He would never be snared as I was.
Will you cast a drift, like us?
No.
My misfortune was to make it home.
You'll be welcomed by my beautiful wife.
Bathed.
Anointed.
Made soft.
To learn the hardest lesson.
I'd left a poison in her heart years
before.
A good part of her heart had gone.
She and her lover had plotted my murder
for years.
Odysseus.
Yes.
My son Arrestes.
Did he avenge me?
My lord, how could I know?
I'm still trying to get home.
Don't make my mistake.
Don't walk on the front door expecting
garlands and praise.
Come in disguise.
Take your time.
It's us.
Do you see?
I know what I have to do.
Some of what you have to do.
My prophecy is not for the Ariers.
Back to the ship.
Sail southwest past the sirens.
Their song glures your men onto the rocks.
They all die.
I won't let that happen.
I'll blot their ears with wax.
Past the sirens, you choose between the
Whirlpool Caribdis and the monster Scylla.
The Whirlpool in the sea takes all of your
lives.
The monster in the cliffs, only six.
But your determination to not sacrifice
any more lives kills all of them.
I'll do what I have to.
At the end, when starvation and mutiny
threaten, they demand to land where the
sun god grazes his cattle.
They slaughter Apollo's herd.
Zeus kills them for it.
Do you see?
I'll stop them.
Why do you value these men's lives more
than those you've already lost?
I can still save them from the gods.
But not from themselves.
What is that?
You are a buried crew.
Demanding you share their dishonor.
Let's go!
Leaving so many fallen comrades.
I have to save the rest.
What's happened to them?
Did they leave me here?
Are they coming back?
Did you do something to them?
I'm sorry.
You told me not to eat the lotus flower.
Just tonight.
So you can get some sleep.
And tomorrow, when you're ready,
you'll remember.
You'll remember your crew.
And your family.
Family.
A wife.
Do I have a wife?
So I'm a lad, though.
Strangers don't come in here.
Screen or no screen.
After three years of feasting together,
we're far from strangers.
Are you trying to marry me or ruin my
reputation?
Melanto can be discreet.
I'm actually here out of concern for your
reputation.
Oh?
Everyone sees how hard you work.
So steady progress.
But every night, you've been unraveling
that work.
Leave us.
You can't expect her to be loyal to a
master she never even knew.
I expect her to be loyal to me.
Then she will be.
Then you marry to me.
Slaves have no choice but to be loyal to
the future.
And this is a household waiting for a
master.
Just as Ethica's a king and waiting for a
king.
Ethica's king is coming back.
No, he's not.
Do you know that as a boy, I tried to go
with him to Troy?
He never told me that.
This is refused to let me.
He knew that Ethica needed a future
without him.
And he saw me as part of that future.
I'll never tell other suitors about
your...
perception.
Finish your weaving.
It's time to let him go.
I wish you wouldn't marry someone who
loves someone else.
Your loyalty to Odysseus is one of your
finest qualities.
I love you.
I want you to choose me and end all this.
You can't tell me you're not tired.
The waiting, the uncertainty.
You've done your duty.
Year after year after year.
It's time to think of yourself.
It's time to live again.
That's what Odysseus would have wanted.
I'll take care of all your needs.
And my son?
The throne as he is.
He's the heir.
Unless we have a child of our own.
Where is Telemachus?
He's gone inland to visit his grandfather.
He's gone for years with his father.
Where?
He's gone to Sparta.
To Minalaus.
Well, should we go there?
No.
Too loud, Melantis.
I told you you're a coward!
He was listening!
No, no!
I was coming for Argus.
I told you that dog stays there.
Go back to the farm.
When we need your pigs, we'll send
Melantis.
You're no longer welcome in this palace,
old man.
My answer to my mistress.
Does she even know your name?
Now go.
Telemachus will have to come back by the
temple at Pylos.
You take your man away from there.
Well, as you can stay and try and charm
the queen.
I don't think so.
He needs to die on that road.
And Iris has a plan.
Iris!
I need everyone and his party dead in a
ditch.
Throat's open.
Telemachus and his men will be ready for
the bandits who work the road between here
and Pylos.
But if some of them took the temple from
the priests before they arrived,
then bring me part of Telemachus' proof.
His nose.
Would you know him only by his nose?
His ears, too.
Who taught you?
My father's swine herd.
A swine herd?
Asma's loyal servant.
Odysseus left his most loyal servant
behind.
He always was the smartest.
Only one Agamemnon ever listened to.
Should have listened harder.
Can I ask what happened to your brother?
His wife betrayed him.
He murdered him.
What did you do to him?
He sent arrestees.
He killed them both.
But he killed his own mother?
He avenged his father.
You don't have to worry.
And your mother has nothing in common with
Clytemnestra.
Maybe not.
But the suitors have convinced the elders
it's time she remarried.
It's not a good time for an empty throne.
He heard the stories, people from the sea.
Have you been raided?
Not yet, but they did tax.
They do seem closer.
The spotter's ready.
What about Ithaca?
She'll be able to raise an army,
defend herself.
Someone's got to take the throne.
Then the battle is there, not here,
son.
You've run from the problem.
I left your mother the mercy of the
suitors.
Should I hire mercenaries?
Go back and kill them all?
Murder rich and powerful guests in your
own home.
You'd be exiled.
What then?
You must evict them without violating
Zeus' law.
I have to take the throne.
I have to know if Odysseus is alive.
This is nothing to do with the father
you've never known.
You have to lead, son.
No matter what's happened to Odysseus.
You need to remember.
No, I don't.
I don't need to know the truth.
I'm happy here with you.
And why are you gathering the bones of
your old ship to make a raft?
Remember your crew.
Your journey.
I heard the song of the sirens.
Put the wax in the men's ears.
Not for me.
Tie me to the mast.
Why?
I want to hear the sirens' song.
No.
It's a bad idea.
No one's ever heard the song and lived.
That's why it's a good idea.
I'll be the first.
No matter how hard I plead, do not untie
me until we're well clear.
Check the men's ears.
A week's rations for the first.
Yes, sir!
What was the siren's song?
All the things he wanted to be.
Then, all the things he wished he'd never
wished for.
Ah!
It was the delicious itch you go to
scratch.
The find that's under the skin,
you can't reach it.
So the delicious itch becomes unbearable.
I told you what you most want...
is what you most can't have.
And what you most can't have...
is what you already had...
and lost.
It was the song of all the promises I
failed to keep.
And it told me I don't really want to go
home.
My water ahead!
Corribed us.
A monstrous whirlpool.
Hoist the sails!
Come on, let's go!
It's a wizard's job!
Can we head out to sea?
It's already got us!
And don't go!
We want to have a roost movement!
We might make that canyon.
It's too narrow.
Make for the whirlpool.
If you steer down the slope, we can make
enough way to shoot out the other side.
Don't be afraid.
We can do it.
No.
No!
We're making for the channel.
We're making for the channel!
Prepare
to hold water!
On my signal!
We did it!
You guys...
Keep us straight!
You knew!
And you didn't tell us!
If I told you, you wouldn't have chosen
this way.
And those men would still be alive!
No!
We'd all be dead!
You had no right!
I had every right!
And every responsibility!
The whirlpool would have destroyed the
ship and all of us!
This way we live!
Some of us live!
Yes!
What else did Tyrese just tell you?
I'm going to put in there.
We can't land there.
That's the sun god's isle.
We need repairs!
These men are exhausted!
I lost six shipmates!
You're going to put in and rest up on dry
land.
You're all going to die!
You asked me what Tyrese has told me.
He said you're all going to die.
If you slaughter the sun god's cattle,
which graze on that island, you'll all
die.
That's fine.
We'll put in.
We'll cook our own provisions.
We'll pick fruit.
We'll get water.
Nothing more.
Swear to it.
All of you.
See?
The wind took us right in.
We'll rest up.
Do the repairs.
We'll set out as soon as the wind changes.
Grab that line.
Did the crew keep their promise?
Yes.
For a long time.
But the wind never changed.
The steady onshore breeze that made it so
easy for us to land.
Made it impossible to leave.
And our provisions ran out.
Did you think if you ate quietly,
the sun god wouldn't notice?
We thought you wouldn't notice.
I'm not the problem.
I wanted you to live.
Tyrese has told you.
Cersei told you.
The gods told you.
You gods learn speak in ways we
understand.
Who doesn't understand pain?
Or blood or death?
When you watch your men die, do you see
chance or do you see consequence?
I see consequence.
I see my failure.
What if their deaths aren't your failure
for theirs?
I lead them.
I led them here.
For no led you.
Why do you put yourself above the gods?
Why do you claim responsibility?
Why don't you want to go home?
What do you expect?
They ran out of food.
Have some pity.
My pity is what put us on this damn
island.
I told you what would happen.
Yes, you did.
And we decided we would rather drown than
starve.
Well, now's our chance.
The wind has dropped!
The calm was just long enough to lure us
out on the Poseidon's ocean.
Under Zeus's sky.
The last thing I remember was the harsh
hand of Zeus.
I
don't know what happened to my men.
Yes, you do.
Exactly what you told them would happen.
I washed up on your shore alone.
You washed up on your shore alone?
I washed up on my shore with some of your
boat and none of your crew.
Half dead, unconscious.
I watched you lost for days and two weeks.
I knew the lotus would ease your awakening
so that your pain was more of the body
than the mind.
And it did.
You liked it so much.
You ate it so willingly.
And as I cared for you...
Thank you.
I came to love you.
How long have I been here?
I kept telling myself to stop giving it to
you that you were strong enough to
remember.
How long collapsed on me?
You were so happy.
You were happy.
We were so happy for years.
Years?
Seven years.
You fed me lotus flower and held me
captive.
I saved your life.
I rebuilt your body.
I just couldn't bring myself to rebuild
your mind.
You have been happy.
Your heart was just always somewhere else.
And your mind was bound to follow
eventually.
How could you?
The lotus clouds the mind and saps the
well, but it doesn't change who you are.
You weren't ready to go home for whatever
reason.
I am now.
As I always knew you would be.
Now?
You were clutching something when I found
you.
Your hand wouldn't open for weeks.
You'd call out.
Mostly to Athena, but sometimes you would
say another name.
You're
a man who needs to control his fate.
But you cannot control this.
You must give yourself to the storm.
Give yourself to Poseidon.
And take your punishment.
Just won't let him kill you.
Give up the fight.
Give up control and live.
And to leave a face you've never yet made.
Odysseus.
Where am I?
Don't you recognize your own home?
Just welcomes you, strangers.
How many are you?
Half a dozen.
Need a meal?
Hand supplies.
For the road.
Where are you headed?
We need pigs.
We're going all the way to Pylos.
Are you pilgrims?
Do we look like pilgrims?
I don't see them.
Very well.
It's just a man's hour for you,
Emil, but these pigs aren't mine to sell.
Oh, don't worry.
We're not paying.
Give my greetings to your mother.
Tell her, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for Troy and for everything that
has happened.
I'm sorry I had no news of your father.
No, you had news.
Not of where he is, but who he is.
And no more than ever, I hope,
to one day meet him.
Where are your watchdogs, old man?
I'm burning their bodies.
Can Zeus offer you food, Drake,
stranger?
Were you attacked?
The dog saved your farmhands.
We burned his brothers first.
What happened to Ithaca?
Darkness.
Zeus' laws smashed to pieces.
A kingdom without a king since my master
died.
Your master?
Odysseus.
Hero of the Trojan War.
But Odysseus is alive.
Because I'm a father, I hope!
No more, no more!
No more, no more, no more, no more,
no more, no!
Dilemicus.
Dilemicus, Dilemicus.
He's in danger, and I can't help him.
There must be others.
Odysseus' son.
The powers is controlled by suitors.
No one is still loyal to Odysseus.
What about the queen?
Beautiful wife Penelope.
Held hostage by the worst men.
Soon to be forced into marriage.
What can she do without even her son?
Yeah, drink.
What's the danger to Dilemicus?
He's on his way back from Spartan.
The suitors send bandits to Pylos to
ambush him at the temple.
Give me food for the road.
You'll never catch up with the bandits.
If I can get to Pylos before Dilemicus
arrives, I can warn him.
Why are you helping?
If I tell you, don't be angry.
I served with Odysseus at Troy.
Really?
He was a harsh taskmaster.
Oh, but fair.
Fair and worthy of following.
You loved him?
Like a son.
Well, he's not dead.
She's coming home.
Soon?
Bringing vengeance.
Bringing it all.
I'll talk.
You don't want people realizing where you
are.
Well, maybe we shouldn't have brought a
guard.
We'll be glad we did if we have trouble on
the road.
You may have sent me.
Find that beggar.
Your men must wait out here.
The weapons, too.
His use welcomes you, strangers.
Have you traveled far?
Not that far.
You're here to rest for the night.
We're here to make sacrifice to Athena.
Then whatever hospitality you can offer
might be considered.
Of course.
Get that beggar out of here.
He has a message for me.
You may have sent you.
Yes, sir.
But what's the message?
He's private.
These men are pr- These men are pr-
This is your moment to leave, old man.
You got to be a stranger.
I already spared one old man this week.
But he was blind.
I won't spare him.
Let's go.
It's not bad for a beggar.
No one's born a beggar.
We'll take this priest's robes.
Put him over your armor.
Help me with his body.
We have to leave him.
No.
We have to slip out.
That's not how you honor the dead.
That is how you stay alive.
He was my teacher.
He might have been Athena in disguise.
His name was Mentor.
And when you are safe, we'll travel to the
unknown west.
And we will honor him.
These men were sent by the suitors.
There will be more of them we need to get
on the road.
By night?
Safer than staying here.
Mentor is at the heart of Athena's oldest
temple.
For now, we'll honor him in flame.
So how does a beggar come to know Mentor?
I told you.
I wasn't always a beggar.
You have wise eyes.
Athena's eyes.
Don't look for gods and men.
You'll just be disappointed.
Well, then tell me who you are.
My name is Sinon.
I'm an old soldier who fought under your
father at Troy.
You knew my father?
I've been taking orders from him for
longer than I care to remember.
Wait, he's alive?
He's alive.
Well, where is he?
He's close by.
He sent me ahead to assess the situation.
Well, mother's not gonna believe.
No, you can't tell her.
What, nothing?
Tell her.
Tell her he decided it's time she
remarried.
He doesn't need to test my mother.
How can he doubt her?
He doesn't.
But she has every reason to have forgotten
him.
Are there any loyal servants?
Some.
When Odysseus shows himself lost.
We need to gather the suitors at the
palace.
That's never a problem.
You have gifts for Menelaus?
Yeah, on my ship.
Good.
Come back as a prince.
Call a banquet.
I'll be there.
What will you do with the banquet?
The bag.
The clearest view of a man is from below.
How many suitors are there?
It doesn't.
If all of these men are like you,
then...
He doesn't have any men.
But it's just you?
And you?
It's
back.
It's back.
Who's seeing this?
Everyone's seeing this.
It's Salaamicus!
My queen!
Sure, your place is up there.
It's true.
You're home.
I'm back.
I thought tonight we could celebrate.
If we have anything left to celebrate
with.
Don't worry.
My brave suitors will shower us with gifts
to honor your return.
So glad to see your safe return.
Glad to see you on your feet.
It's about time we took you back to the
palace.
What did you hear about your father?
Nothing.
A story is from the war, but no one knew
what happened to him after he left Troy.
I'm sorry, Mom.
Everyone in Sparta is talking about a
coming catastrophe.
An age of darkness brought on by people
from the sea violating Zeus' law.
Some stories are true.
Our civilization is collapsing.
Menelaus is concerned that we can't raise
an army with an empty throne.
So we came up with a plan.
What plan?
The one way to get the suitors to leave.
It's time for you to choose.
You want me to remarry?
If you remarry, the other suitors will
leave.
And then I'm only dealing with one of
them.
I'm almost of age.
I'll tell the elders that I learned of
Odysseus' death in Sparta.
Menelaus will back me up and they'll let
me assume the throne.
So you deny your father and I leave my
home and go live with one of these snakes.
That's your plan.
Would you have a better one?
Lock the door, set a fire and burn the
bastards.
Do you think if I remarry, life goes back
to the way it was?
That world is gone.
And in this one, they're not giving up
power to you.
Or Odysseus.
If he returned, he'd have to kill him.
Like you will.
If I kill them, their families will demand
revenge.
I'd be exiled.
And without me, the throne will be lost.
Because only a man can sit on it.
Empty throne?
I've been sitting on that empty throne for
20 years.
My knowledge, my years of experience,
that's all nothing compared for the
bristles on your chin.
Do you want peace?
Or do you want revenge?
I want a distance!
A face!
Sing, muse of a face!
A fleet!
Atrore!
Sing, muse of a man!
A man!
You may as go ahead.
Vargas.
You should bury him up on the cliffs.
Where you met?
You're Odysseus.
You're my father.
I'm a beggar.
And you...
are the worthy, beautiful son of Odysseus.
Of whom, when you do finally meet,
he will be so proud.
Welcome home, stranger.
Because the darkness of victory shrouds
the writers' legends.
And make boards to blind beggars of us
all.
Accept the hospitality of Zeus.
Get the strangers some food.
No, sir.
I'll just make the rounds with a bowl.
Had to invite another one of these filthy
platelikers to dinner.
What's one more beggar at this feast?
We need to kill him before he regains his
position with the elders.
Ow.
Get him to grab one of the weapons.
He's not the same young pup we used to be.
When you come back tonight, let me cut his
top.
Fuck off, old woman.
Please.
It's been days since I've eaten.
I told you to fuck off.
We can't be generous with food that's not
even yours.
There's no room in your bowl.
Yes, there is.
So, there is.
There you go.
I suppose you want something from me now.
No.
I have something for you.
You have something from me?
You have something from me!
What could a filthy old plateliker like
you possibly have that I could want?
Actually, it's yours.
I was asked to return it.
It's not mine.
No?
Where did you get this?
Don't turn your back on me!
It's Ineos.
You can't treat a beggar like that.
It's Zeus's law.
Zeus's law.
You think this is a guard?
You think this is a guard in disguise?
Are you?
Are you a guard?
Plateliker?
No.
I'm a veteran of the Trojan War.
Veteran of the Trojan War?
And what's your name, veteran?
Sinai.
Does that name mean something to you?
No.
I use it to honor the bravest young man I
ever met.
Sinai?
Well, not just Shepard's boy.
I don't remember that.
Yeah, you wanted you to take his place.
Where did you find this?
Where he'll soon be.
Where is that?
Here it is.
Enough!
The feast is done!
Let's go.
It's not mine.
A queen would like to speak with you.
Stay until everyone's left in the fires of
love.
Hello, traveler.
My queen?
Melanthal, have your clay awash the
stranger's feet.
That's not necessary.
My husband insisted we honor guests as
family.
You know of the disease, my husband?
Of course.
Who are the songs?
I was at Troy, ma'am.
The songs probably seem silly.
They make me cry.
Why?
For what was lost.
For lives?
And the years.
Everything.
Did you know of disease at Troy?
I did.
Was there some detail of how he dressed?
Something he wore?
He wore a strange pin.
Strange?
Beautiful.
But out of place.
Describe it.
I'll get more water.
It was a beautiful gold pin.
A figure of Athena encircled by vines.
Did he wear it off?
He never took it off.
How is it that you made it home when a
disease could not?
I'm not home.
Not yet.
Why not?
It's not always an easy thing,
a homecoming.
That's as true for Odysseus as for me.
The Odysseus I knew would have found or
fought his way back to me no matter what.
What if the Odysseus you knew lost his
way?
What if one night in a strange city he saw
things that made him think the home he
knew couldn't possibly be there anymore?
What if when he left the belly of the
horse
and opened the gates of Troy
he saw ten years of rage pour into that
city in one night?
A gift, an offering of peace that they
took into their home.
We violated all that's ever sacred between
people and turned a viper
into a hunt.
To burn the walls of Troy was to burn the
world entire including his home.
What if he knew that very night
as he walked through fires of anarchy and
pain
and in the days of sweaty celebrations to
follow?
What if he knew exactly what he'd done?
What all of you had done?
One man's idea.
One man's trick.
To break Zeus's law forever.
We lived in a world of palaces and trade
and language blind to its beauty until we
broke it.
You are the people from the sea?
Yes, my queen.
The breaking of Zeus's law is spreading
and I play our age of bronze is collapsing
and maybe he couldn't bear to see the
ruins of what he'd done anywhere,
at least of all his home.
But Odysseus is alive and he'll be here
when you need him most.
I've been living in his ruins long enough.
Bring the suitors at dawn.
Remove the arms from the hall.
In a few hours one suitor will be happy
and the rest angry vengeful men.
Ron's draws a man on so we'll have no
weapons at the trial and the doors will be
locked.
I'll marry whoever completes my challenge.
How will we take on the suitors?
Not we.
They'll have the loans on my hands.
Or you'd face exile.
Won't you?
Just make sure they can't get those
weapons.
I'll see to it.
Even an arm, there are so many of them.
And you won't have a weapon.
Oh, I'll have a weapon.
Your mother's seen to that.
Gather the servants you trust.
Lock the arms in the upper storage room.
Who seems interested in the outcome?
But what's the trial?
For years.
While my husband's been gone, you've
commandeered this palace for your
feasting.
Your excuse was you wanted to win my hand
in marriage.
As I listened to your party, your fight
corrupt my servants and disrespect my
home, I wanted nothing more than for
Odysseus to return and see all this for
himself.
But last night, I realized he's not here
now.
He never will be.
So...
I stand, ready to marry anyone here who
can string this hunting bow and shoot an
arrow through those 12 axes.
Step up.
And show me who you are.
You may as.
Who's first?
Give me the bow.
It can't be done by you.
If it's a boy like Odysseus do with ease,
then you do it.
I'll wait my turn.
Why don't we warm the bow and oil it?
This bow hasn't been strung in years.
Your turn.
There's no need.
My queen has made her point.
We can't replace Odysseus.
Some of us have always known that.
Some of us would have followed that great
man to Troy if he'd let us.
But he never came back.
So choose the best of us here.
All of us who failed your test.
I haven't.
Somebody get these beggars out of here.
The doors are locked until the trial is
over.
The trial is over.
I want to try.
Give it a rest.
He has a right to try.
He may as well.
You're making a mockery of your mother's
wishes.
My mother's wishes are for you all to
burn.
I'm sorry.
Look at the expert at work.
Wait a minute.
Come on!
Oh, old man, forget it.
Odysseus.
Surely your place is down there.
Stop!
Is it him?
It's him!
Where are the weapons?
They're at the store room.
Get them!
What are you waiting for?
I'm going to kill them all!
Look out!
I told you.
Too loud, cowherd.
No!
Get the shields!
You
thought you could kill us all?
As long as I kill you.
Finish this.
Dad!
When you get to Hades, tell my men I will
head west and honor them.
And tell Senneth...
I gave you back your shame.
What
happened?
Did it beat them?
Did she dead?
We broke the fragile bonds between men.
And for centuries of darkness to follow,
the stories of Troy will only be sung.
Odysseus.
My love, you get that?
At last.
In the end.
To see my beloved if I could.
One last time.
No.
No, no, you can't.
You can't.
Not now.
Not now, please.
You can't die.
I'm not deaf.
Exile.
Till I'm against who we became.
Take your fastest ship.
And greatest crew.
And head for the horizon.
Jason, he is kidding, son.
Why will the stories only be sung?
Because songs will be all they have to
remember those of us who could write.
Civilization will rise again.
The new dawn will break over the darkened
world.
And our mistakes will once again be
forgotten.